IRFAN SHAIKH

MERN STACK DEVELOPER

OBJECTIVE

With one year of experience as a mern stack developer with good working knowledge in several types of Database Management, I am passionate about coding and like to learn new things. Strong creative and analytical abilities, as well as team player with a keen eye for detail

WORK EXPERIENCE

MERN Stack Developer | Inkprog Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

June 2022 - Present

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Worked on a big project and finished it on schedule.
- Implemented a user-friendly Web application that exceeds the criteria of the client's specifications.
- Collaborated with developers to create user flow charts.
- Produced clear, effective code in order to meet the requirements.

BEEJ Network - Backend Developer

- Contributed to a three-person team's successful completion of the project for Beei Network.
- Designed based on the RestAPI standard and website requirements, APIs were created for the Beej Network website.
- Developed founders APIs and fulfilled customer requirements with successfully executed code.
- Creating a relational database for the founder and investors and making adjustments as needed are responsibilities.
- Set up email and one-time password (OTP) login authentication for investors and founders.

Ivy Reality - MERN Stack Developer Intern

- Managed collaborated with three team members to effectively design the Ivy Reality website.
- This website was successfully completed before the deadline with good attention.
- Worked to improve the website's usability and responsiveness across all displays (web, laptop, tablet and mobile).
- The contact page and landing pages for this website were created, and they include a slider, form validation, and some redirection features.

LMS - MERN Stack Developer Intern

- Established the authentication for both new and existing users..
- In order to hold the required data, a database utilizing MongoDb was created.
- Developed functionality for including a new book, Return a book for a specific user and view the history of all returned and unreturned books

Junior Salesforce Consultant | Igra Technology Pvt. Ltd.

June 2019-Nov 2020

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Administer, troubleshoot, and maintain the connected Salesforce platform on a daily basis.
- worked on the Salesforce Lightning and Salesforce Classic Platform
- made their business's workflows more logical, effective, and user-friendly by improving the user experience and incorporating these features
- adapted and modified the Salesforce Platform for Multiple Users

SKILLS

- HTML,CSS
- JavaScript
- React JS
- Mongoos

- Node.Js
- Express.Js
- MySQL, MongoDb

EDUCATION

Rajiv Gandhi College | Nanded

2015 - 2018

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

• Project is Ms-Cit Software system - We cloned the government information technology course known as MSCIT using C# technology and added an MSCIT multiple-choice question.